让我们来看看食物的更多细节，这是人类生活的基本要求。
Let’s look in a bit more detail at food, a fundamental requirement for human life.
联合国预测，到2050年，我们将需要增加70％的粮食
The United Nations predicts that by the year 2050, we will need a 70% increase in food
生产。并非所有这一切都是由于人口增加。很多是由于要求
production. Not all of this is due to increase population. A lot of it is due to the requirements
我们星球上的许多人拥有的食物比他们目前所拥有的更多
of many of the people on our planet to have more food than they’re currently getting
也许更高质量的食物，更高热值的食物。所以，增加的一个很大的要求
and perhaps higher quality food, higher calorific value food. So, a big requirement to increase
食品生产和70％是在30年内实现的大幅增长。
food production and 70% is a massive increase to be achieved in something like 30 years.
很明显，我们需要食物供人们食用。我们还需要动物食物
It’s pretty obvious that we need food for people to eat. We also need food for animals
去吃。它们是我们食物链的一部分。所以，我们生产的很多食物都被吃掉了
to eat. They are part of our food chain. So, a lot of the food that we produce is eaten
通过动物，反过来，我们许多人吃这些动物。
by animals and in turn, many of us eat those animals.
对食物来说有点令人惊讶的用途就是把它放在汽车里。有一个很大的运动
A somewhat surprising use for food is putting it in cars. There’s quite a movement to
将食品，尤其是玉米转化为乙醇，我们将乙醇加入气体中
turn food product, particularly corn into ethanol and we put the ethanol into the gas
我们汽车的坦克。因此，我们生产的食品竞争很激烈。
tanks of our cars. So, there’s a lot of competition for the food that we produce.
当然，我们想要人们吃的食物，但也需要食物
Absolutely, we want food for people to eat but there’s also food that’s required
喂养动物，还有喂养汽车所需的食物。
to feed animals and there’s also food that’s required to feed cars.
随着人口的增长，我们城市的规模也在增长。城市变大了;他们
As our population grows, so too does the size of our cities. The cities get larger; they
侵占生产性农田。他们把这块土地从粮食生产中拿走了，因为我们
encroach on productive farmland. They take that land out of food production because we
在它上面建造房屋和公寓，这意味着我们可以减少种植粮食的土地。
build houses and apartments on it, so that means we have less land on which to grow food.
现在，这是一个问题，因为总的来说我们需要种植更多的食物而我们正在消除
Now, this is a problem because overall we need to grow more food and we’re removing
土地是粮食生产的必需资源。
land which is the essential resource when it comes to food production.
另一个问题是农民作为一个人口正在变老。这个统计数据来自
Another issue is that farmers as a population are getting older. This statistic is from
我的国家，澳大利亚，我们在这里查看这个直方图，它显示了平均值
my country, Australia, and we look at this histogram here and it shows that the average
农民的年龄远远超过50岁。没有年轻人从事农业作为一种职业
age of farmers is well above 50. There's not young people moving into farming as a profession
或作为一种生活方式。我国澳大利亚的一个非常可怕的统计数据是下一个
or as a lifestyle. A very scary statistic in my country, Australia, is that in the next
十年来，有一半的农民将要退休。那么，谁将在陆地上做这项工作
decade, half of the farmers are going to retire. So, who’s going to do the work on the land
生产我们需要的食物？
to produce the food that we need?
因此，机器人技术的一个机会是帮助和解决这种食品生产
So, one of the opportunities for robotics is to help and solve this food production
问题。一种应用是转换这些用于工业的大型机器
problem. One application is to convert these large machines which are used in industrial
规模粮食生产。而不是驾驶它的机器上有人，
scale food production. Instead of having a human being on board the machine driving it,
我们把它变成一个机器人车辆，这样它可以一周7天，每天24小时独自驾驶。
we turn it into a robotic vehicle so it can drive all by itself, 24 hours a day, seven days a week.
我们可以做的另一件事是更换用于喷洒农作物的人力驱动机器
Another thing we can do is to replace human-driven machines which are used to spray crops in
田地和我们喷洒农作物，以消除昆虫和杂草害虫。而不是做不分青红皂白
the field and we spray the crops to eliminate insect and weed pests. Rather than doing indiscriminate
如你所见，喷涂我们可以拥有更智能的机器人系统
spraying as you see here, we can have much more intelligent, robotic systems which move
或许通过作物更慢，并使用识别昆虫害虫的视觉传感器
perhaps more slowly through the crop and use vision sensors which identify insects pests
或者我们称之为杂草的不良植物，并将适当的化学物质施用于其中
or undesirable plants which we call weeds and apply the appropriate chemical to just
这种情况不是随处可见，而不是无处不在。这是一个巨大的环境
where that occurrence is, not indiscriminately, not everywhere. That’s got huge environmental
由于我们可以减少化学品的数量，因此它也带来了巨大的成本效益
benefits and it’s also got huge cost benefits because we can reduce the amount of chemical
需要应用。
that needs to be applied.
使用化学除草剂来控制杂草导致了意想不到的结果
The use of chemical herbicides to control weeds has led to an unexpected outcome and
也就是说，许多杂草物种现在已经进化出对这些标准除草剂的抗性。
that is that many weed species have now evolved a resistance to these standard herbicides.
这对已经发展起来的农业系统提出了特殊的挑战
That presents a particular challenge to an agricultural system which has developed over
几十年，并且非常依赖于使用除草剂来控制杂草。所以，也许吧
decades and become incredibly reliant on the use of herbicides for weed control. So, perhaps
智能机器人可以识别土壤中的杂草并将其机械破坏，如图所示，
smart robots could identify weeds in the soil and destroy them mechanically as shown here,
实际上是打扰了杂草周围的土壤来破坏杂草。
actually disturb the soil around the weed to destroy the weed.
这是我们在QUT的实验室研究项目中开发的机器人视频。
Here’s a video of a robot we’ve developed in a research project in my lab here at QUT.
这是我们的杂草喷涂机器人的早期原型。这是一台非常小的机器。它的
This is an early prototype of our weed spraying robot. It’s a very small machine. It’s
由相机和其他类型的传感器引导。它可以沿着裁剪行导航并应用
guided by cameras and other sorts of sensors. It can navigate along crop rows and apply
除草剂只在需要的地方。
herbicide only where it’s required.